DCinside 기타미드갤러리.
나엘남캐
와이키키 해변
- 오하우 -
- 저것 좀 봐
- 저기 누구지?
Look out!
빨리 나와!
- 너 뒤좀 봐!
- 상어야
Hey behind you!
Get out of the water!
Hey, behind you!
애론!
재미 없거든?
Aaron, that wasn't funny.
누나만 속은거야
You're the only one
who isn't laughing.
구조 요원들이 보면
너 쫓아 낼거야
The lifeguards are going
to kick you off the beach
뭐, 어쩌라고
if they see you.
Yeah, whatever, Liz.
하와이엔 상어가
진짜 산다고, 멍청아
We're in Hawaii. They have real
sharks here, you idiot.
I'm off to claim
my next victim.
난 다른 먹잇감은
필요 없어
(Hawaii Five-O
theme song plays)
Hawaii Five-O 2x04
Mea Makamae (Treasure)
Original Air Date on October 10, 2011
♪ Hawaii Five-O 2x04 ♪
Mea Makamae (Treasure)
Original Air Date on October 10, 2011
== sync, corrected by elderman ==
♪
나엘남캐 한글자막/싱크
수정금지/자유배포
Okay, fellas, grand opening
is next week.
여러분, 저희 다음 주에
개업 한답니다
저희 음식 한 번
시식해 보세요
You get to taste test
my menu items.
오늘은 매콤한 새우
볶음밥이랑 새우 그라탕
Today we got shrimp jambalaya,
shrimp and grits,
shrimp pupu, shrimp kabobs,
shrimp fried rice.
새우 튀김, 새우 꼬치
새우 튀김밥이에요
아기들 한테는
내 손맛이 들어간
And for the keiki's,
my classic corn-battered
옥수수 가루 입힌
새우 꼬치가 있답니다
shrimp on a stick.
사람들이 새우 트럭을
찾는 이유는
Okay, you know why shrimp
trucks are so popular?
Is because people know what
they're going to get
메뉴들이 뭔지 다
아니까 오는거야
when they go to one--
they're going to get
마늘 맛, 매운 맛 튀김
레몬 & 버터
garlic scampi, hot and spicy,
lemon and butter.
3개만 있어야지
31개가 아니고
Three flavors, not 31.
이 섬은 경쟁이
엄청 치열하다고
But this island is crawling
with competition, man.
다양한 메뉴들이
이런 포화 시장에서
A diverse menu can only make
my product stand out
내 사업을
돋 보이게 해줄거야
in an oversaturated market.
얼른 먹기나 하고
어떤지 말해 줘
Now dig in to the grinds,
and tell me what you think,
please.
Jambalaya has got some kick.
매콤한 새우가
꽤 맛있더라
Mm-hmm.
Try it.
먹어봐
그거 알아요?
You know what?
위장도 참 튼튼 하시네
저건 무기로 써야죠
You got a cast-iron stomach,
but that should be weaponized.
You got any water in there?
물 없어?
- 소다수 아님 그냥 물?
- 숨도 못 쉬겠다
Sparkling or flat?
Seriously, I can't
breathe right now.
- 아무거나 줘
- 갔다 드리죠
Anything.
Coming right up.
Man.
있잖아요..
I know you didn't call me here
just for lunch.
점심이나 하자고
나 부른거 아니잖아
So, what's on your mind, son?
무슨 말 하려고?
아버지가 우 팻이랑
제임슨 주지사를 만난
I need to know why
my father was meeting
with Wo Fat and
Governor Jameson.
이유를
알고 싶어요
Okay? I need to know what was
being discussed on that video.
그 때 무슨 말을
했는지 알아야 돼요
국방부에서 소리 추출
하고 있다고 했잖아
I told you I got the DOD
working on extracting the sound.
쉬운 일은 아니지
음성이 싹 지워졌으니
But it's not an easy job,
the audio was scrubbed.
- 한 달이나 됬잖아요
- 걔네도 군인이야
It's been four weeks.
Yeah, well, it's the DOD, son.
- 그렇게 빨린 안 돼
- 누가 분석 하는데요?
Nothing happens overnight.
Who's your guy in
digital forensics?
I'll give him a call.
- 전화 해볼래요
- 그럴 필요 없어
That won't be necessary.
조금 더 기다리면
뭐 좀 나올거야
Just give me some more
time on this.
We'll have some answers
soon enough.
맥개럿 입니다
McGarrett.
시체 검시소
DANNY
What's cooking, Max?
뭐 요리해요?
One right hand
of a John Doe murder vic.
피살자의
오른 손이요
대략 30세에서
40세 같네요
Approximately
30 to 40 years old.
- 나머지 몸은요?
- 해안 경비대에서
- Where's the rest of him?
- The Coast Guard is dragging
the shorelines of Waikiki Beach
where the hand was found.
손이 발견된 해변을
따라 수색 중이에요
왜 이게
살인 사건인데요?
Why are we tagging
this guy a homicide?
이 사람.. 상어밥
된 거 아닌가?
This guy-- it's a hand.
He could be shark food.
혈액에서 높은 수치의
납을 발견 했어요
Blood had elevated
levels of lead,
사실은 총에 맞아
죽었단 말이죠
indicating the victim
was indeed shot.
The hand was then
severed postmortem
손은 뼈를 자를
정도로 예리한 걸로
by something sharp enough
to cut through a bone.
사후에 절단 된건데
아마 배 프로펠러가
몸을 조각 냈겠죠
Most likely a boat rotor
cut through a body dump.
All right, what are you doing?
알겠어요..
지금 뭐해요?
이런 젖은 시체는
MAX
We're dealing with a wet body,
하루가 지나면 바깥 쪽
피부가 떨어져 나가요
so after 24 hours
of submersion,
the skin separates
from the dermis.
Try to roll a print
지문을 찾는데
아무것도 안 보여도
and you only get
a black smudge.
피부의 최상층엔
아직 굴곡이 남아 있어요
But the outer
layer of the skin
actually maintains its ridging.
껍데기만 있으면
다 돼요
All you need is an extra set of
hands and you're in business.
You're putting the guy's
hand like it's a glove.
피해자 손을
장갑 처럼 낀거에요?
Max, that's disgusting.
맥스, 역겨워요
하지만, 굉장히
효과 있죠
Yes, but very effective.
좋아, 나왔네요
Sweet. We got a hit.
The victim's name
is Blake Spencer.
피해자 이름은
블레이크 스펜서에요
Okay, got a local address?
집 주소 있죠?
블레이크 스펜서가
여기 산다고 들었는데요?
Sir, we're told
Blake Spencer lives here?
술집 윗 층
아파트에 살아, 왜?
Sure, it's the apartment
above the bar. Why?
오늘 아침 살해된 채로
발견 됬어요
Blake Spencer was found
murdered this morning.
Murdered?
살해라고?
I don't get it.
이해가 안 되네
- 착한 애 였는데
- 관계가 어떻게 되세요?
He was such a good kid.
How well did you know Blake?
블레이크는 그냥
세입자가 아니었어
Blake was a lot more
than just a renter.
난 그 애를
친구로 생각했네
I considered him a friend.
저 커틀라스
보이지?
You see that cutlass?
영국 군용 칼이야
That's Royal Navy.
블레이크가
서인도 제도에 침몰한
Blake got it off an 18th
century British schooner
18세기 영국
범선에서 가져 왔어
that sank off
the Antilles.
방 세 밀린거 봐줘서
고맙다고 선물 받았지
He gave it to me as a thanks
for not going after him
for back rent.
잠수부 였네요?
So Blake was a diver?
여기서 제일 실력있는
인양 잠수부였어
Damn good one.
Best salvage diver
who ever walked though my door.
Salvage diving.
배를 인양한다..
- 꽤 험한 일인데
- 수입도 짭잘했지
That's, uh,
that's dangerous work.
Lucrative, too.
세계 도처에 있는
침몰지를 다녔으니
Blake found wreck sites
all over the world.
수집가들이
줄을 섰었지
Had collectors lining
up to buy from him.
그런데 왜 이런
아파트에 산데요?
So why's he living in
an apartment above a bar?
어머니가 아파서
하와이로 돌아 왔대
He moved back to Hawaii
after his mom got sick.
와이파우 근처
요양원에 모셨다던데
Had to put her in a
rest home near Waipahu.
You know, that didn't keep
him out of the water though.
그래도 일은
계속 하고 싶었나봐
From what I could tell he was
going after a new wreck.
어떤 난파선을
찾는다고 들었어
- 그게 뭔지 아세요?
- 아니
He tell you what it was?
Nah.
그 애가
관심 있었던거면
But if Blake was interested
in it,
뭔가 대단한 걸거야
it had to be something big.
Here you go.
Thank you.
- 이 방이네
- 고마워요
감사합니다
Thanks.
- 난 밑에 있겠네
- 아늑한 곳이네
I'll be downstairs
if you need me.
Lovely place.
로리더러 어머니
찾아 보라고 할게
I'll get Lori
to track down the mother.
All right, what's
missing here?
이상한 건 없어?
Oh, besides a box spring,
매트리스랑
TV는 있는데
a television, anywhere to sit,
I have no idea.
앉을데는 없어,
잘 모르겠다
Blake traveled the world
diving shipwrecks,
난파선에서
숨겨진 보물을 찾으려고
세계를 돌아다닌
사람이야
looking for
hidden treasure.
Don't you think he would have
kept something?
보물 좀 남겨놓진
않았을까?
아픈 어머니를
부양해야 되니까
He's got a sick mother
to support.
다 팔아
버렸나보지
Maybe he had to
sell everything.
Or he was sinking everything
into his next treasure hunt.
아니면 새로운
보물 사냥에 다 썻거나
배랑 수영 장비에
카드 돈을 다 써버렸어
Guy maxed out his credit card
on boat and equipment rentals.
12 grand alone last month.
저번 달에만
12,000달러야
보통 침대 밑에
이런건 없는데
You know, this is
generally not the kind
of reading material you find
under a mattress.
- 암호 같은 걸 찾았어
- 항해 좌표 일거야
Looks like codes
and stuff.
I bet they're
navigational coordinates.
잠수 지점을 숨기려고
암호로 바꿔놨겠지
Blake probably encoded them
to protect his dive sites.
골치 좀 썩히겠군
꽤 좋은 걸 찾았나봐
A lot of trouble to go through.
Must be something pretty valuable.
You hear that?
이거 들었어?
들어봐
Huh?
Listen.
You know, the treasure
Blake was looking for--
그 친구 찾던 보물은
이미 찾았나 보네
looks like he already found it.
응, 이거 때문에
죽었을 수 도 있어
Yeah, and it might
have got him killed.
리리우 칼리니 요양원
- 와이파우 -
Excuse me,
Mrs. Spencer,
실례합니다,
스펜서 부인
I'm Officer Lori Weston.
전 로리 웨스턴
요원이에요
Is it okay if I come in
and talk to you?
잠깐 얘기 좀
나눌 수 있을까요?
Please, come in.
어서와요
마실거나
먹을 거 줄까요?
Can I get you
something to drink?
- Or eat?
- No, thank you.
- 아, 괜찮아요
- 샌드위치 먹어봐요
I have a sandwich here.
My son likes one
when he comes home.
우리 아들도
맛있게 먹어요
아들이요?
Your son?
- 블레이크요?
- 네
- You mean Blake?
- Yes.
He should be home any minute.
곧 올거에요
학교만 갔다오면
항상 배고파 한다니까
He's always so
hungry after school.
Blake's still in school?
- 아직도 학교를 다녀요?
- 지금 6학년 이에요
Sixth grade now.
His teachers say he's one
선생님이 우리 애가
반에서 제일 똑똑하대요
of the smartest
in his class.
Do you have children?
- 아이 있어요?
- 아뇨, 없어요
No, ma'am. I don't.
Well, you have plenty
of time for that.
뭐, 자기는
시간 많잖아?
Did you say
하고 싶은 얘기가
있다면서요?
you wanted to talk
to me about something?
무슨 일 있어요?
Is something wrong, dear?
하와이 왕실 박물관
- 오하우 -
It's amazing.
끝내준다, 한 때는
바다의 왕이었는데
I mean, one day you are
the king of the ocean, right?
The next thing you know,
나중에 보니, 박물관
천장에 걸려있고
you' hanging from
the ceiling in a museum
and children are looking
어린애들이 자기 민감한
부위를 보고 있다니
at your private parts.
Yep, kind of puts
things in perspective.
잘도 묘사해놨네
저기요
Excuse me.
Five-O, right?
You called about the coins?
파이브 오 맞죠?
동전 땜에 오셨다해서
Yeah, I'm Steve McGarrett,
내, 전 맥개럿이고
윌리엄스 형사입니다
this is Detective Williams.
Danny, please.
- 대니라고 불러요
- 전 아사노 박사에요
Hi. Dr. Gabrielle Asano.
I'm the museum's curator
전 역사-문화 담당
책임자에요, 반가워요
of historic and cultural affairs.
Nice to meet you.
Nice to meet you, too.
- 저도 반갑습니다
- 반가워요
Very nice to meet you.
진짜 반갑네요
Danny.
- 대니, 동전은?
- 아, 죄송해요
- Huh?
- The coins?
Oh, sorry.
Um...
Have...
이..이런거
본 적 있으세요?
you ever seen
anything like this?
What's the matter?
너 왜그래?
음, 보니까
As a matter of fact... I have.
뭔지 알아요
The Princesa Del Mar
was a Spanish trade galleon
'프린세사 델 마'는
스페인 상선이에요
1682년에
영국 해적들에게
lost at sea in 1682,
after it came under cannon fire
from English pirates.
대포 공격을 받고
표류했죠
These coins
이 동전들은
그 배에 있던거에요
are from that wreck.
Spanish galleon?
Is it possible
스페인 상선이요?
그런게 하와이 쪽에서
침몰 했다고요?
that something like that could
have sunk in local waters?
그래요
Absolutely.
배를 수리 하려고
여기서 방향을 바꿨대요
The galleon's believed
to have diverted here
for repairs
after the pirate attack.
Salvage divers have been
looking for the wreck for years.
잠수부들이 그 배를
몇 년동안 찾았죠
Right, so what you're saying is,
whoever recovered these coins
동전을 찾은 사람이
배도 찾았을거란 말이죠?
may actually have
found the Princesa?
Pirate ships
해적선, 대포, 보물..
and cannonballs
and treasure.
I thought this stuff only
happened in movies.
이런건 영화에만
나오는 줄 알았어요
I can assure you
the treasure is very real.
보물은 실제로 있어요
And very valuable.
굉장한
값어치도 있고요
Valuable? How, uh, how much
are we talking about?
액수는 얼마나 돼요?
On the collectible market,
the coins would fetch
수집가들 사이에선,
동전은 몇 천 불이에요
maybe a couple thousand...
동전 하나에요
...each.
And the Princesa
배에 이런 동전은
몇 톤은 있을거에요
was believed to be carrying
several tons of them.
That's a lot of money.
- 엄청난 돈이네
- 살인 동기도 되지
That's a lot of motive.
제가 동전들 잠시
보관하면 안 될까요?
Gentlemen, would you mind if
I held on to these for a while?
박물관 차원에서
진품인지 알고 싶어요
On behalf of the museum,
I'd like to authenticate them.
죄송해요, 동전이
사건 증거라서요
I'm sorry, but these coins are actually
evidence in a murder investigation.
그래, 그래도..
Yeah, but...
동전 하나 준다고
큰 일 안 나잖아
I'm thinking it won't hurt to
just give her one little coin.
괜찮으니까
받으세요
Go ahead.
It's fine.
It's just one coin.
딸랑 동전 하나잖아
- Why are you losing your mind?
- I'm not losing my mind.
- 왜렇게 화를 내?
- 화 안 냈어
If you want to ask her out,
ask her out.
그냥 맘에 들면
데이트 신청을 해
- I'm just saying.
- Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
내가 언제
맘에 든댔어?
Who said anything
about asking her out?
나중에 또 만나려고
동전 준 거 잖아?
Come on.
You left Dr. Asano a coin
so you have a reason
to go back and see her.
- 이해할게
- 어, 아니거든?
- It's fine.
- Uh, that's not true.
I left her a coin
because she might
수사에 도움이 될까봐
동전을 주고 온거야
be able to help
with our investigation.
Really? You know
what you should do?
진심이냐?
그냥 가서 커피나
한 잔 하자 그래
You should ask her out
for coffee.
I don't want... I'm not...
내가 뭐.. 그런 관계
필요 하댔어?
I'm not looking
for a relationship.
커피가 왜 관계야?
그냥 음료수지
Coffee's not a relationship.
It's a beverage.
That's not true.
Every single relationship
아냐, 어떤 관계든
다 커피로 시작해서
starts with a cup of coffee.
저녁 식사 후
영화를 보고
Then it's dinner
and a movie. Okay?
Next thing you know, you're
divorced, you're moving
나중엔 이혼 당해서
딸 보러 여기 살게 된다?
to Hawaii so you can see your
daughter every other weekend.
우리 팀에 이런 거
전문인 애 있잖아?
You need to talk
to somebody professionally.
- Okay?
- I do. You.
너도 걔한테
상담 좀 받아, 대화 끝
And now the session's over.
그러지 좀 마
No, the session's
not over, Danny.
너도 여자 만나야지
커피면 좋은 시작이야
You need to get back
on the horse, and a cup
of coffee's a good place to start.
What are we doing?
- 너 뭐해?
- 잠깐이면 돼
Need to make a stop.
Just wait here.
Hi, Cat.
안녕
- Thank you for meeting me.
- Yeah.
- 만나줘서 고마워
- 응
Got that for you.
- 꽃 사왔어
- 와, 이거봐라
Oh, look at that.
Thank you.
고마워
What do you need
this time?
- 이번엔 뭐가 필요한데?
- 알아 보겠어?
What do you
make of this?
Our victim was a wreck diver,
and we think
피해자가 여기 있는
잠수지 에서 죽은거 같아
that he may have been killed
at one of his dive sites.
이게 좌표가 맞다면
해독은 쉬울 거야
Okay, well, if you're right
about these being coordinates,
then the cipher
should be easy to crack.
I'll run cryptography
and let you know what I find.
한 번 돌려보고
알려줄게 / 고마워
Mahalo.
이쯤이면 고마워서
저녁 산다 해야 되지 않나?
See, this is usually
the part where, you know,
you ask me out
to dinner as a thank you.
Oh, no... absolutely.
Anywhere you want, okay?
너 가고 싶은데로 가자
근데 그 전에..
But before you decide,
I, uh... I need to ask
you one more favor.
부탁 하나만
더 할게
Sasabune, omakase menu.
사사부니에서
일본 코스요리야
Yeah.
부탁이 뭔데?
Now, what's the favor?
Fine.
그래.. 음..
Um...
you remember Joe White?
- 조 화이트 기억나?
- 옛날 당신 상관?
Your old commander?
Yeah.
진주만에서 SEAL 팀
훈련 감독 하신다던데
Yeah, yeah. Uh, I heard
he's overseeing
SEAL Team training at Pearl now.
Yeah, he is.
맞아, 그게..
Uh...
look, he submitted a piece
of intel for analysis, okay?
그 분이 분석 때문에
자료를 제출했어
It's a video I'm trying
to pull sound from.
소리를 복구 해야 되는
비디오 인데
DOD has been sitting
on it for weeks now.
국방부에서 오랫동안
소식이 없어서
I just... I was hoping you
could check the status for me.
네가 좀 확인해
줄 수 있냐고
Look, if the request
came from Joe,
그 사람 자료는
나도 못 보는거야
I'm sure it's
being handled.
Could you just check
for me, please?
날 봐서 확인
해주면 안 될까?
위에서 당신만
못 보게 하는거야?
Do you think someone at DOD
is giving you the runaround?
I don't know. I don't
know what's going on.
잘 모르겠어
나도 무슨 일인지
Yeah. Okay.
그래, 알아 볼게
Good timing.
딱 맞춰 왔어
방금 바다에서 피해자
시신을 수습했는데
The Coast Guard
just recovered the rest
of Blake Spencer's body
at sea.
맥스가 폐 조직에서
헬륨 가스가 나왔대
Max found traces of helium
in the lung tissue.
So we know Blake was killed
right after a mixed gas dive,
배로 올라온 뒤
바로 살해 됬으니
- 폐에 헬륨이 남은거야
- 맞아, 이것좀 봐
which means deep water.
Exactly.
And check this out.
He still had
his dive bag on him.
아직 잠수용 가방을
매고 있네, 안에 뭐야?
What is that?
There's something in there.
연구소에 검사 맡겨 놨어
지금 들르려고
I had everything sent
to the crime lab for analysis.
I'm heading over there now.
Hopefully, whatever's
뭐가 나오던 범인 찾는데
도움이 되겠지
inside that bag
could lead us to our killer.
Good. Hey.
어머니 한테
나온 거 있어?
Did you get anything
from the mother?
Not exactly.
- 별 거 없어요
- 어떻게 받아들이셔?
How'd she take it?
말 안 했어요
I didn't tell her.
What? What are you talking about?
- 왜 안 했는데?
- 치매 노인이셨어요
- Why not?
- The woman's suffering from Alzheimer's.
She thinks Blake's
11 years old.
블레이크가 11살 이래요
아무래도 더는 무리에요
There's no way she'd
be able to process it.
Uh, how'd the
museum work out?
- 박물관 일은요?
- 대니, 네가 말 해봐
How'd it go, Danny?
How was the museum?
그만 좀 해라
Enough, okay?
피해자가 중요한
난파선을 발견했고
Turns out that our victim
uncovered a major shipwreck.
So we're thinking that somebody
got hip to what he was doing,
누가 그걸 알고
따라가 죽인 모양이야
followed him out to the site
and killed him.
We need to find out who else
knew about that treasure.
그걸 아는 사람이
누군지 찾아야 돼
An old wallet?
- 낡은 지갑?
- 가방에 이거 밖에 없었어요
It's the only thing I
found in the dive bag.
And last I checked,
17th century pirates
제가 알기로는..
17세기 해적들한테
뉴욕에서 산 가죽제
지갑은 없었을걸요
didn't carry leather wallets
made in New York City.
Right. So it
belonged to Blake?
- 블레이크 건가?
- 아닌 것 같아요
I don't think so.
But based on
the oxidation,
산화 된 정도를 보면
I'd say this thing
was submerged
물 속에서 최소 50년은
더 됐을거에요
for at least 50 years.
I may be able to date
it more accurately
더 정확한 시간을
얻으려면 이걸 봐야 돼요
once I'm done
processing these.
Wow, there was
money inside it.
안에 돈도 있네
이래도 잉크는 거의
다 날라갔을 거에요
The wallet prevented the bills
from deteriorating completely,
but the ink is mostly gone.
Either way, he didn't get
this off the Princesa.
그 배에서 찾은 건
아니라는 거죠
All right, so he could
have been diving
다른 난파선에서
작업을 했었던거네
another wreck
when he was killed.
I'll let you know when
I'm done processing.
- 결과 나오면 알려줄게요
- 고마워, 찰리
Yeah, thanks, Charlie.
Hey.
있잖아
Um, I need a favor.
부탁 좀 하자
This is my
activity log
내 경찰서 DB
로그인 기록이야
for the HPD database.
The login that's
circled here
여기 나도 모르는
IP에서 접속 된게 있어
was made from an IP address
that I don't recognize.
Now, I managed
to back-trace it
내가 프록시 써서
추적해 봤는데
through a couple of proxies,
but I can't get past a VPN.
사설망은
못 뚫겠더라고
Can you help?
도와줄 수 있어?
친,
Chin, if someone hacked
into your account,
계정 해킹 당한거면
보고 해야죠
you need to notify
the department.
I will-- if the threat's legit.
보고 할거야,
정말 해킹이면
Okay. I'll see what I can do.
- 알았어요, 찾아 볼게요
- 고마워
Thanks.
맥주 고맙소
Thanks for the beer.
Mm-hmm.
Thanks for nothing.
저도
참 고맙네요
Can I buy you a drink?
- 제가 한 잔 살까요?
- 지켜 봤어요, 경찰 이세요?
Seen you making the rounds.
You a cop?
- 로리 웨스턴, 파이브 오에요
- 지미 콜러입니다
Mm-hmm. Lori Weston, Five-O.
Jimmy Koller.
Nice to meet you,
반가워요
Well, that's an
interesting ring.
반지가 신기 하네요
백금 같은 거에요?
What is that, white
gold or something?
Oxidized silver.
은 이에요, 영국 군함
페가수스에서 찾았죠
Got it off the HMS Pegasus.
Right. Thought you
might be a diver.
잠수부 인 줄
알았어요
You... by any chance,
you know a Blake Spencer?
블레이크라는 사람
혹시 아세요?
As well
as the next guy.
혼자 다니는 사람인데
전문가라고 들었어요
Blake mostly kept to himself,
but I heard he was a real pro.
Hmm.
You hear anything about him
diving the Princesa Del Mar?
프린세사 델 마는
들어 보셨나요?
No.
아뇨, 그 배 찾는
사람은 알고 있죠
But I know a guy who's been
hunting the Princesa for years.
Sunk a lot of money
into finding her, too.
거기에 돈도
많이 쓴 사람이에요
And who might that be?
그게 누굴까요?
I'm Jesse Billings,
president of Voyager Marine,
보이저 마린의 대표
제시 빌링스 입니다
the world leader in deep water
shipwreck exploration.
저희는 난파선 탐색의
전문가 입니다
Today, I'm going to offer you
a once-in-a-lifetime opportunity
오늘 일생에 한 번인
투자 기회를 소개 하죠
to invest in what just may be
역사상 가장 장대한
보물 사냥입니다
the greatest treasure hunt
of all time.
For the past
two years,
지난 2년간, 배의
투자자를 모았어요
Billings has been
pitching investors
on the hunt for the Princesa.
He's already sold
millions in shares.
이미 주식만
엄청나게 팔았죠
Which means he had a lot to lose
if someone found
누가 먼저 찾으면
잃을 게 아주 많겠군
the wreck before he did.
여보세요?
At Voyager Marine,
This is Detective Williams.
저희의 세계 정상급
연구원들과
our world-class team
of researchers,
기술자, 잠수부들이
바다를 찾고 있습니다
technicians and divers
search the oceans for treasures
영원히 잊혀졌던
보물을요
once thought lost forever.
빌링스가 자원이
넘쳐나는데
Here's what I don't get--
with all the resources
that Jesse had,
how was Blake able
어떻게 블레이크가
먼저 배를 찾은거죠?
to beat him to
the Princesa?
이거야, 이 사람이
블레이크네
That's how.
That's our dead diver.
빌링스 밑에서
일을 했었군
Blake worked
for Jesse Billings.
배를 찾은게 아니에요
동전을 훔친거죠
So he didn't discover
the Princesa;
he stole the coins
from his boss.
Yeah, and you know what?
I bet Jesse was pretty upset
사장이 그걸 알고
무척 화났겠지
- when he found out about it.
- Thank you.
근데..
문제가 하나 있어
Um, only one problem
with that theory.
Just got off the phone
아사노 박사한테
방금 전화 받았는데
with Dr. Asano
from the Bishop Museum.
우리가 찾은
동전이 가짜래
The coins we found
in Blake's apartment are fake.
내가 살인을 했다고요?
- You think I killed Blake Spencer.
- He's a mind reader.
- 저희 다 알고 왔어요
- 내 직원을 왜 죽이겠소?
Yes, that's what we think.
Why would I kill
my best diver?
그 보물이 사기인 걸
알았으니 죽였겠죠
I'll tell you why--
because Blake found out
that the treasure hunt
you hired him for was a scam.
이 사진 좀 볼래요?
Why don't you take
a look at this photo?
- 어디서 났소?
- 블레이크 집에서요
Where did you get these?
We found those
in Blake's apartment.
당신 피부색처럼
동전도 가짜야
Those coins are about
as real as your tan.
You know what? I bet you
haven't even dipped a toe
몇 년 동안 물에
발도 안 담갔죠?
in the water in years.
그래도 사기는
되게 잘 치셨네요
But I have to commend you
on a somewhat elaborate scam.
바다에 가짜 동전을
버려 놓고
It's pretty good-- you dump a
bunch of fake coins in the ocean
to convince your investors
that you have found
프린세사 델 마를
찾았다고 사기를 치다니
the Princesa Del Mar.
실제로 그 배는
못 찾았죠?
But you didn't find
the Princesa, did you?
And Blake realized
the coins were fakes,
블레이크가 그걸 알고
동전을 가로챈거고
and that's why he took them.
And you knew he was going
to open his mouth
입을 열려고 했으니
죽여야 됬겠죠
about it,
so you had to kill him.
전..
I've, uh...
I've salted a few shipwrecks--
난파선 이야기는
꾸민 게 맞소
I admit that--
but I had no idea
그래도 블레이크는
몰랐을거요
Blake knew it.
I swear.
맹세해요
- 지폐 때문에 불렀어요
- 좋아
- Got some news on those bills.
- Great.
What is it?
뭔데?
IP 주소
추적 해봤어요
I traced that IP address
you gave me.
- 가정집 주소 였어요
- 누군지 알아?
That login was made
from a home computer.
- Okay. Do we know the owner?
- Yeah.
네, 코노였어요
It was Kono.
코노는 퇴출
당했잖아요
Kono was dismissed
from the force.
What's she doing
using your password
형 비밀번호로
뭐 하는거래요?
to access
HPD files?
아, 맞다
그거 나였다
You know what?
That was me.
I was at Kono's house
that day.
그 날 코노집에서
사건 본다고 접속했어
I used her computer to check up
on some case work.
고마워
- Thanks.
- Right.
지폐는
어떻게 된거야?
So what do we know
about those bills?
Took some work,
but I was able
조각을 모아서
지폐를 완성했어요
to piece together
one of them.
- 5달러 자리인가?
- 맞아요
- What is that, a five?
- Good eye.
꽤 흐려도
잉크가 아직 있어요
It's pretty faded, but
there's still some ink there.
이것도 보세요
And wait till
you see this.
The Hawaiian overprint note,
issued in 1942.
하와이안 달러는
1942년에 발행 됬어
After Pearl Harbor,
the decision was made
진주만 폭격 후
섬에 있는 모든 지폐를
to pull all the paper money
on the Islands and destroy it,
- 이걸로 교체했지
- 왜?
replacing it with this.
Why?
일본군이 쳐들어와서
차지할 수도 있으니까
Because, had the Japanese
invaded Hawaii, they would have
been able to seize huge sums
of U.S. currency.
하와이 도장 찍어놓고
쓸모없다 하면 땡인거지
But this way, the
Federal Reserve
just declares the Hawaii-stamped
bills worthless. Problem solved.
Of course, the invasion
never happened.
물론 침략은 없었고
전쟁 후에 회수 됐어
When the war ended, the
overprint notes were recalled.
- 이걸 어떻게 찾은거야?
- 다른데서 찾았겠지
Okay. How did Blake get this?
Not from the Princesa.
He must have been diving
another wreck.
지갑이 물 속에서
50년 된거면
If that wallet
was underwater for 50 years,
he may have been salvaging a ship
that sunk during World War II.
세계 2차대전 때
침몰한 배 같아
Okay, hang on a second.
Catherine decrypted
잠깐, 캐서린이
좌표들을 해독했대
the coordinates from
Blake's notebook.
장소를 봐
Look where they fall.
It's a straight line from Oahu to Maui.
오하우에서
마후이 가는 길이네
난파선은 항해로
같은 데 있을거야
His wreck must
have sunk
along a ferry
or shipping route.
진짜 넓네
That's a lot of ground to cover.
- 여기서 죽었을거야
- 제가 찾는법 알아요
And Blake could have been killed
at any one of these sites.
I may know
how to find which one.
모아나 보트 대여사
- 호놀룰루 항 -
According to Blake's
카드 기록을 보니
여기서 배를 빌렸더군요
credit card company, he rented
one of your salvage boats.
난파선 잠수부들
자주 와요
Yeah. Most of
my business
is wreck divers.
블레이크 반납 날은
내일 이에요
Blake wasn't due back
until tomorrow.
Did he say where he planned on diving?
I didn't ask,
- 잠수 얘긴 아세요?
- 나도 몰라요
and he wouldn't
have told me if I had.
그 사람은 자기
일 얘기 안 하거든
Blake didn't talk
to anybody about his work.
Okay, Mr. Julian, that boat
is now a crime scene,
줄리안 씨, 배가
범죄 현장이라서요
so you think you can help us
find where it is?
배 위치를
알 수 있을까요?
All my rentals are equipped
with tracking systems.
제 배들은 위치 추적
장치가 달려있어요
Just a second.
I'll pull it up.
기다려요
알아볼게요
Okay, perfect.
Great.
Is there a problem?
왜 그래요?
배에 있는 송신기가
고장 났나봐요
The transponder on his boat
isn't working. Must be busted.
Or Blake disabled it
because he didn't want
누가 못 따라오게
일부로 그런 것 같아요
anyone following him to his dive site.
Okay, listen to me.
보트 번호랑
생긴 거 알려줘요
Give me the tags
and a description of the boat.
Okay, if Blake's killers
haven't sunk the boat,
범인이 배를 안 버렸으면
어딘가 떠있을거에요
it's got to still be out there
somewhere, right?
6588, 호놀룰루 섹터
명령 하달 바란다
6588, Sector Honolulu.
Request op and position.
섹터 호놀룰루, 6588
작전 상태 양호함
Sector Honolulu, 6588,
북위 21도
45.3분
operations normal, position
21 degrees, 45.3 minutes north,
동경 157도
25.4분
157 degrees, 25.4 minutes west,
오차 범위 1분 내
목표 발견
one plus one zero minutes
to bingo.
고도 유지하며
선박 탐색중
Continuing parallel search
for the overdue vessel.
So let me ask you a question.
뭐 좀 물어보자
여자가 프로필에
'연애 중 아님' 해노면
If a woman leaves
the relationship status
on her profile page empty,
does that generally mean
혼자라는 거야?
애인 있다는 거야?
that she is single
or that she is taken?
Is this about the hot
doctor from the museum?
그 이쁜 박사님
얘기에요?
I mean, you should
ask her out.
그냥 데이트
신청해 봐요
What, he... he talked
to you about this?
쟤가 말 해줬어?
우리가 고딩이냐?
What, are we
in high school?
아뇨, 근데..
- No, we're not, but...
- Hey, guys.
해안 경비대에서
블레이크 배를 찾았대
Coast Guard just called.
They found Blake's boat
40 miles east of Oahu.
- 배에 움직임이 없다더군
- 아, 제가 발표 할래요
Pilot says it is not moving
with the currents.
Ooh!
Even I know what that means.
- 배가 돛을 내린거에요
- 참 잘했어!
- Means the boat is anchored.
- That's right.
그 아래에 난파선이
있는게 분명해요
So the site Blake was diving
must be right below it.
Yeah, there's only one way
to find out.
- 직접 찾아봐야 겠군
- 야, 거기 되게 깊은데야
Whoa, whoa, whoa.
Those are deep waters.
혼자 가려고?
미쳤냐?
You'd be crazy
to dive that by yourself.
Yeah, I would.
That's why I'm taking a partner.
파트너 데리고 가야지
Partner?
파트너?
Steve, glad you called.
연락 잘 했어!
Chin, it's not
a good time.
오빠..
지금은 곤란해
너 내 비밀번호
왜 쓴거야?
I want to know why
you were using
my password to access
HPD records.
I wanted to see
my case file.
- 내 사건 파일 보려고
- 어째서?
Why?
나 복직 하는데
도움 되는 게 있나봤어
'Cause I want to know
what they have on me.
See if there's any chance of me
ever getting my badge back.
- 나한테 왔어야지
- 복직한지 얼마 안 됐잖아
You could have just asked me.
You just got reinstated
a month ago.
Last thing I want to do
is cause you any trouble.
오빠 곤란하게 하기 싫었어
여긴 왜 온건데?
You shouldn't
even be here.
저 사람은
여기서 뭐해?
What the hell
is he doing here?
Lieutenant Kelly.
캘리 경위
It's nice to see you
got your badge back.
복직 하니까
멋있어 보이네
Yeah, some of us,
we weren't so lucky.
우리는 좀..
운이 없었지
You got ten seconds
to turn around
차 타고 꺼지는데
10초 준다, 레이
and go back to your car, Ray.
- 나 그냥 갈까?
- 아니요
You want me to leave, Kono?
No.
잘가라
Bye-bye.
착한
사촌 오빠네
Good ol' cousin Chin.
He's back with
Five-O, that right?
파이브 오에
다시 돌아갔지?
네
Yeah.
그 파일 넘기려고
오빠 비밀번호 쓴거야?
And, uh, you used his password
to get me those HPD files?
그 방법이 좋았던 거
같진 않은데..
I can't decide whether that
was really resourceful...
or incredibly stupid.
엄청나게
멍청한 짓이였어
정보를 달라해서
제가 준거 잖아요
Look, Frank,
you came to me for access,
I got you access.
Chin won't be a problem.
- 오빠는 제가 알아서 해요
- 그래야지
I'll make sure of it.
You better.
Your cousin starts
poking his nose
네 사촌이 캐고 다니면
우리 둘 다 곤란해 질거야
where it doesn't belong,
that's gonna be a problem
for all of us.
난 자네처럼 섬세하게
처리 못 한다고
I might not handle it
as delicately as you.
블레이크의 배
피가 있네요
We got blood.
저기 튀긴 자국이 있고
여기서 쓰러졌을 거에요
Gunshot spatter and a pool here
where Blake must have dropped.
Why right here?
왜 여기지?
잠수 중이나 배 밖에서
죽일 수도 있잖아
Could have set up
while Blake was diving,
and popped him right when
he got out of the water.
탄환이 여깄네요
9mm 자리에요
Got a slug here. Nine mil.
탄도 검사 해봐
All right,
check out this trajectory.
쏜 사람도 분명히
배에 탔을거야
Shooter had to be on the boat
for this to line up.
Which means he either forced
his way on or...
- 강제로 피해자를 태웠거나
- 믿을 만한 사람이었겠죠
Or Blake trusted him enough
to have him on board.
So, uh, you hear
anything back from the DOD about
that surveillance video yet?
국방부에서 아직
비디오 소식 없어요?
소식 없어
Still no word.
What?
왜?
I just can't shake this feeling
일부로 저한테
숨기시는거 같아서요
there's something you're not
telling me, Joe.
집중이나 해
Well try harder
'cause when we break 150 feet
150피트 밑에
가스 마시고 내려가면
and the narcosis sets in,
you're gonna have
그 생각 말고 할게
많을거다, 알겠어?
enough trouble keeping your head
straight without those thoughts
bouncing around in it.
Understand?
네
Yeah.
Okay. I splash first.
내가 먼저
들어간다
We're gonna follow
the anchor line down.
돛만 따라 갈거니까
잘 따라붙고, 집중해
Stay close, stay focused.
- Now let's go see what Blake found.
- Yes. sir.
- 뭘 발견했나 보자고
- 알겠습니다
♪ ♪
- 맥스 손 필요해요?
- 고마워요
Max, you need a hand?
Oh, thank you,
but it is against
protocol
근데 규정상 검시관만
다룰 수 있어서요
for anyone but the ME
to handle the remains.
도와준단게 아니고
진짜 손 필요 할까봐..
No, no, I don't want to help.
There's actually a hand
right there if you want,
if you need a hand.
진짜 재밌네요
Ah, that was very humorous.
차는 1930년대
군용 엠뷸런스 였어요
Hey, guys, so the car
is a late 1930's
Packard model ambulance,
military issue.
So, this guy
could have been a soldier?
이 사람
군인 이었을까?
I don't know. Max?
- 전 몰라요, 맥스?
- 저도 모르겠네요
Well, I can't answer that.
But I can tell you that we have
a full skeleton here.
그래도 뼈들은
전부 모았어요
180cm 정도의
남성이에요
It's male,
roughly six feet tall.
사망원인은..
범죄는 아니에요
As for the COD, well,
it wasn't anything nefarious.
Just a few broken bones.
- 뼈만 좀 나간거 뿐이죠
- 신원은 확인 못 하나요?
Any chance we can get
an ID on him?
Teeth are intact, however,
if he is as old as the car
치아는 멀쩡한데
타고 있던 차랑
동시대 사람이면
that we found him in,
then most likely
그렇게 오래 된
치아 기록은 없으니까
we don't have dental records
that go that far back.
신원을 밝히기엔
어려울거에요
So ID'ing him would
be a long shot.
We could always take him
to JPAC.
JPAC 사령부로 가자
거긴 30년대 기록도 있어
They got X-rays and records
going all the way back
to the '30s.
이 사람도 군인이면
찾을 수 있겠지
So if this guy served,
he's probably in the system.
찾아야죠
Let's hope so.
Blake died salvaging this car.
그래야 블레이크가
죽은 이유를 알거에요
We need to find out
why it was worth killing for.
그래, 너 짐싸라
Okay. Bag him up, kid.
You're going with.
같이 가자
Yes!
아싸!
JPAC : 미 합동 전쟁포로 및
실종자 확인 사령부
Did you know that JPAC
JPAC 연구소가
세계에서 제일 큰데요
is the largest forensic
lab in the world,
and that it specializes
exclusively
사후 신원 확인도
전문으로 하거든요?
in postmortem
identification?
사실 제가
제일 좋아하는 분야죠
Which, incidentally,
is my favorite type
of identification.
토하게 봉투 갔다줘?
You need a paper bag
or something?
에?
아, 죄송해요
Huh? Oh, sorry.
완전 꿈꾸는 거
같아서요
It's just this place
is like my Graceland.
알았다
Okay.
- 기념품은 사지마
- 여러분
But no souvenirs.
Gentlemen.
Hi, I'm Dr. Tallridge.
톨리지 박사입니다
과학 총괄이에요
Scientific Director.
Joe White.
- 조 화이트요
- 맥스 버그만이에요
Max Bergman.
JPAC에 오신 거
환영합니다
Max, welcome to JPAC.
음.. 연구소로 가서
한 번 살펴 봅시다
Um, why don't we find
a lab table
and see what you got here.
All right,
I researched archives
마우이 뉴스나
각종 언론사에서
for the Advertiser
and The Maui News.
1938년 자료는
다 찾아봤는데
Went all the way
back to 1938.
바다에서 잃어버린
차 얘기는 없었어요
No articles
mentioning anything
about a car
lost at sea.
해군 역사 사령부에서
뭘 발견했어
I found something with Naval
History and Heritage Command.
These guys, they keep records
각종 사건 보고를
전부 저장해 두거든
of every incident report
ever filed.
This was dated
이 사건은 1942년
7월 19일 날짜네
July 19, 1942.
해군 수송선이 마우이로
보급 작전중 폭풍을 만났는데
A Navy transport vessel
was delivering supplies
to Maui when a big storm hit,
바다에 흘린
화물중에는..
sending some of the cargo
overboard.
1939년식 육군
엠뷸련스가 있었군요
Including a 1939 Army ambulance.
You found it.
찾았네요
근데 왜 블레이크가
이 차를 찾은거지?
I did find it,
but it doesn't explain why
Blake was salvaging that car.
I don't get it.
안에 좋은 게
있었나보죠
Maybe there's something
valuable inside.
아니, 엠뷸런스는
전사자만 싣고 있었대
No, I mean, according
to this report,
the ambulance was transporting
a body for burial.
사망자는
로버트 머피 대위였어
The deceased was a
Captain Robert S. Murphy.
뼈 잔해가 이 사람
시체였을까요?
You think those were
his remains inside?
글쎄.. 관이 아니라
운전석에서 찾았거든
I don't know. I mean, there were
bones in the front seat.
There was no casket
in the back.
잠깐만요
Wait a minute.
I've seen this guy before.
이 사람 봤어요
I was just a little girl
when my father died.
아버지 돌아가셨을 땐
난 어렸었어요
We were living in Maui,
he was stationed at Pearl.
우린 마우이에 살았고
아버진 진주만에서 근무했죠
After the attack,
폭격이 있고나서
it took a few days until we
heard that he'd been killed.
아버지 전사소식을
듣는데만 며칠이 걸렸어요
Dad was supposed
to have been buried
아빠를 가족 납골당에
모시려고 했는데..
in the family plot, but...
결국 돌아오지
못 하셨군요
But he never made it home.
Not knowing where he was,
it always haunted my mother.
어디에 계신지 모르니
어머니가 괴로워 하셨지
우리들도
괴로웠고요
Haunted the rest of us, too.
스펜서 부인..
정말 유감입니다
Mrs. Spencer,
I'm... I'm so very sorry.
No family
어떤 가족도 그런 일을
겪으면 안 됩니다
should ever have to suffer
through something like that.
You've served,
haven't you?
- 군인이었죠?
- 네, 해군이요
Yes, ma'am, Navy.
그럴 줄 알았어
딱 군인처럼 생겼어
I can tell.
You have that
look about you.
My son Blake wants to be
a sailor when he grows up.
내 아들도 크면
선원이 되겠대요
물 밖으로 끌어내질
못 하겠다니까
I can't keep that boy
out of the water.
Mrs. Spencer...
스펜서 부인..
...about Blake...
- 아드님이요..
- 감사했습니다
Mrs. Spencer,
thank you.
We'll, uh, we'll be
on our way.
이제 가볼게요
But she still doesn't know
about Blake.
- 저분 아들이잖아요
- 다 알고나서 말씀드리자
Better to tell her
when we have answers.
- 할아버지를 찾던거네요
- 그 차가 중요했던 이유지
He was looking for
his grandfather.
That's why finding
that ambulance
was so important
to him.
He wanted to give
his mother some closure
어머니를 위해서
그렇게 찾았던거야
by finally bringing home
the body.
Yeah, I understand why it
was important to Blake,
그런데 살인은
왜 당한거죠?
but why would somebody
kill him for it?
- 말씀하세요
- 신원이 밝혀졌어
Joe, go ahead.
Steve, we got a match on those remains.
All right, did it come back
to a Captain Robert Murphy?
로버트 머피
대위 인가요?
No.
마일즈 브로딕 일병
이라는 사람이야
Docs ID'd our man
as Private Miles Brodic.
스코필드에있는
27사단에 복무 했었어
He served with the 27th Infantry
out of Schofield.
Beyond that, I can't tell you
much about him because his file
그 외에는 신상 정보가
70년 넘게 기밀이었더군
has been classified
for nearly 70 years.
그럼, 공개 해야죠
Well,
let's get it
declassified.
A few months into
his enlistment,
마일즈 일병은
복무중 잔 도둑질로
Private Miles Brodic faced
a court-martial
여러번 군사 재판에
회부됬었어
on multiple charges
of petty theft.
41년 5월에
불명예 제대를 했지
He was dishonorably
discharged in May of '41.
제대 후 엔, 킬라니
묘지에서 일을 했어
After his discharge,
Brodic took a job
at Kealani Cemetery.
He was there when the
bombs dropped on Pearl.
진주만 폭격 때도
살아 있었지
섬에 모든 지폐가
하와이안 달러로
He was also there when
the government issued
the order to recall
all the paper money
바뀔 때도
살아 있었어
on the islands
and replace it
with the Hawaiian
overprint note.
Sorry, I don't understand.
무슨 소리에요?
멀쩡한 지폐를 태운 곳이
바로 그 묘지야
Lori, Kealani Cemetery
is where all the recalled money
was sent to be destroyed.
They burned
over a hundred million dollars
여기서 1억만 달러는
넘게 태워버렸지
of it at the crematorium there.
돈이 전부
탄건 아니야
Actually, not all the
money was destroyed.
According to
the military,
군 기록에는, 내부자가
2백만 달러를 빼돌렸대
$2 million was siphoned off
by someone with inside access.
Brodic.
브로딕이요
By the time the MPs got wind
of it, Brodic was long gone.
헌병에서 낌새를 챘을땐
이미 도망갔지
Anybody want to guess how he
snuck the loot off the island?
어떻게 그 돈을
섬 밖으로 빼냈게?
Robert Murphy's casket.
로버트 머피의
관으로요
관이 마우이로 가는걸 알고
안에다 돈을 채운거에요
Brodic knew it was going
to Maui, so he stashed
- his money inside of it.
- Explains why somebody
아직도 쓸 수 있으니
살인이 난거야
would shoot Blake over it.
That money is still
valid currency.
So we find that casket,
관을 찾으면
범인도 찾겠네요
we find our killer.
Anybody want
some shrimp mochi
후식으로 새우 모찌
좀 먹어볼래?
for dessert?
That's, uh, shrimp-
flavored ice cream?
이거 새우 맛
아이스크림이에요?
Mm-hmm.
Huh, that's, that's interesting.
I'm full.
아, 재밌네요..
- 나 배불러
- 저도 괜찮아요
Yeah, I'm good, too,
but thank you.
Shoots.
계산서 줄게
I'll just leave the bill.
I'll settle up with the big man.
- 내가 처리할게
- 고마워요
Thanks, Joe.
이것 좀 봐바
리모 줄리안 기억나?
You guys are gonna
want to see this.
You remember
Remo Julian?
Yeah.
블레이크가 배 빌린 곳
사장 아니에요?
Isn't that the charter operator
that Blake rented his boat from?
Mm. He's also
a very accomplished liar.
거짓말도 잘 하지
Crime lab just finished
processing the boat.
연구소에서
배를 조사했는데
They found the transponder
intact and fully functional.
배에 송신기는
멀쩡히 작동했대
Okay, so Remo was playing
with us
그게 고장 났다고
우릴 속였었어
when he said it
was malfunctioning.
응, 또 있어
Mm-hmm. It gets better.
I hacked into his system,
그 쪽 항해 기록
전부다 해킹 했어
pulled the navigational
logs for his entire fleet.
Turns out there were two boats
at Blake's dive sites
살인이 났던 밤에
배가 두 대 있었더군
the night that
he was killed.
리모가 블레이크를
따라간거야
Remo tracked Blake out there.
리모 줄리안
파이브 오다!
Remo Julian!
Five-O!
이상 무
Clear.
I checked the rest of the floor.
전부 확인 했는데
리모는 없어요
Remo's gone.
Steve!
- 스티브!
- 대니?
Danny?
I think I found Captain Murphy,
머피 대위님 찾았어
피해자 할아버지셔
our vic's grandfather.
돈 챙기고 사람 뼈는
쓰레기 처럼 버려놨네요
Remo took the money and tossed
the bones aside like trash.
Looks like he left
in a hurry, too.
좀 급했나보네
All right, so that's how
he dried the cash, right?
세탁기로
돈을 말렸구만?
- 돈에 피가 묻어있어
- 피해자가 더 늘겠군
Guys, I got fresh blood
on this bill.
This could mean we have
another victim.
이게 그 엠뷸런스에서
나온 것 같네요
Take a look
at this coffin.
Looks like it could have
been in our sunken ambulance.
Doesn't look like Remo Julian
줄리안씨는
취조 못 하겠네
will be giving us any answers.
Looks like COD
was blunt-force trauma
사인은 머리의
둔탁한 외상 같아요
to the head.
팔과 목에 방어흔도
남아 있네요
Victim also shows signs
of defensive wounds
on his arms and his neck.
- 좀 이상하네
- 뭔데요?
Hmm. That's peculiar.
What'd you got?
피부 밑의
상처에요
Subdermal bruising.
피해자 두개골에
상처가 남은 것 같네요
Looks like the fatal blow
left an indentation
on the victim's skull.
Oh.
살인자가 독특한
반지를 꼈었네요
And it looks like our killer
wears a very unique ring.
한 번 보세요
Take a look at this.
- 페가수스가 뭔지 알아요
- 어떻게 알아?
That's the crest
of the HMS Pegasus.
How did you know that?
- 범인을 봤으니까요
- 지미 콜러입니다
Because I met Remo's killer.
Jimmy Koller.
반지가 신기 하네요
뭐에요?
That's an interesting
ring. What is that?
Move in.
Okay, listen,
there's a tiny, tiny chance
네가 90세 생일 전에
출소할 기회가 있는데
that you're going to get out
before your 90th birthday.
But that window
of opportunity
지금 말 안하면
기회는 날라가
is closing rapidly,
you understand?
이제 기회는 없어
축하해
Okay, window's closed. Thanks.
Wait.
잠깐만!
Blake radioed Remo
from the wreck site.
블레이크가 리모를
바다로 부른거야
Said he needed a winch
and a couple guys
뭘 끌어낸다고 장비랑
사람이 필요하댔어
to help dredge something up.
그런 관이 흔한 건
아니잖아?
Right, 'cause
not often you find
a casket at the bottom
of the ocean.
그런 돈 올리려면
사람 좀 필요 했겠지
Especially one
with $2 million in it.
All right, so how long before
you and Remo turned on Blake?
그래서 둘이 짜고
배신한 건가?
원래 세 명이서
나누려고 했어
Hey, Remo and I were willing
to split the money
three ways, but Blake
gave us some line
근데 블레이크가
할아버지 얘길 꺼냈지
that the bones belonged
to his grandfather.
He was just trying
to cut us out.
우리 둘을
따돌리려고
So you killed him.
네가 블레이크를
죽이고
Then you killed Remo
혼자 돈을 가지려고
리모도 죽인거야?
so you could take
the whole $2 million
to yourself, right?
- 도둑은 명예가 없지
- 그 얘긴 진짜였어
No honor among thieves.
Blake wasn't lying.
돈을 신경쓴게 아니야
그게 진짜 할아버지였어
He didn't care
about the money.
And that really was
his grandfather.
He just wanted
to bury the man,
할아버지에게 안식을
주고 싶었던 거 뿐이였어
put the past behind him.
Family plot's still in Maui.
가족 납골당이
아직 있대요
VA's making arrangements to send
the remains there for burial.
재향 군인회에서
식을 준비하고 있대요
All right. Did you
notify the family?
- 가족한텐 얘기했어?
- 직접 말해주려고요
Not yet. I wanted Sylvia
to hear it from me.
- 아들 얘기도 할거지?
- 헛되이 죽지 않았다고요
You going to tell her
about Blake, too?
She needs to understand
her son didn't die for nothing.
할아버지를 마침내
쉬게 해주었잖아요
Because of what he did,
her father can finally
be laid to rest.
조금은 위안이
될거에요
Small consolation, I know.
요즘은 조그만 것도
중요 하다니까
It's times like these, all the
little things help, don't they?
Yeah.
로리, 하기 싫으면
내가 전해도 돼
Listen, Lori, I can make the
notification if you want.
Hey, thanks. No.
고맙지만
제가 꼭 해야 돼요
I need to do this on my own.
It's not the first time
이런 소식 전하는게
처음은 아니에요..
I've had to tell a parent
they lost a child. I just...
hoped I'd never have
to do it again.
다신 이런 일을
안 했으면 했죠
누구에요?
Who's that?
오래된 친구야
That is an old friend.
Excuse me a second.
- 잠깐 갔다올게
- 네
Okay.
Hey.
Uh, dinner's not
until 8:00, and you...
8시에 먹기로 했잖아
옷도 너무 차려입었네
I think
you may be a little overdressed.
Hmm.
Actually, I'm going to need
to ask for a rain check.
저녁은 나중에
해야 될 거 같아
Okay.
그래
Orders came in today,
오늘 명령이 났는데
중앙사로 임시직 발령났어
and I'm being sent T.A.D.
to NAVCENT.
- 밤에 걸프만으로 떠나
- 오늘 밤? / - 응
My flight for the Gulf
leaves tonight.
- Tonight?
- Yeah.
Wow.
Yeah.
그래서..
So...
Yeah.
Anyway, um,
어쨌든..
나 가기전에
before I left, I just wanted
부탁했던 거
알려주려고 왔어
to get back to you
about that thing
that you asked me about.
국방부에
확인해 봤는데
Yeah.
I checked with the DOD,
화이트 소령님한테
받은 거 아무것도 없대
and they said that they haven't
received any intel requests
from Commander White.
You sure about that?
- 정말이야?
- 응
Yeah.
- 유감이야
- 응..
I'm so sorry.
Yeah.
I should probably go pack.
- 가서 짐 싸야겠어
- 잠깐만..
Yeah, listen,
um, Catherine,
캐서린..
저녁 식사 말인데
uh, about this
rain check, uh...
가서 좀 있으면
휴가 나올 수 있지?
you're-you're probably
gonna get some leave
in the next few months.
Why don't we meet
somewhere halfway?
휴가 때 중간에서 보자
뭄바이는 어때?
I don't know.
Mumbai or something?
나 인도음식 좋아해
I like Indian food.
I know, but if your mom
catches you
지금까지 깨있는거
엄마가 알면 큰 일나
up this late,
she's gonna kill us both, okay?
Go to bed, all right?
자러가
And I'm gonna see you
really soon, and I can't wait,
좀만 참으면
아빠 볼 수 있어
얼굴에다
뽀뽀 많이 해줄게
'cause I'm gonna kiss you
all over
your little monkey face, okay?
그래
All right.
대노도 사랑한다
Yeah, Danno loves you,
too, baby.
All right.
끊을게
Okay.
좋았어
Detective Williams.
윌리엄스 형사님?
여기서 뭐 해요?
What are you doing here?
Uh, well, it's a nice night,
아.. 근사한
밤이네요
and I was wondering
if you'd like
저랑 커피 한 잔
하실까 싶어서요
to get a cup of coffee with me.
I would like that.
커피 좋죠
나 잔소리 들을
기분 아냐
Chin, I'm really not up
for a lecture right now.
잘 됐네, 안 그래도
하려고 했어
Good, because I'm not here
to give you one.
너한테 사과할게
I'm here to apologize.
Everything you're going
through right now
네가 겪고 있는 것들
나도 다 겪어 봤어
I've been through myself.
경찰에서 내쫓기니
실망감만 들더라
Getting kicked off the force,
dealing with disappointment,
후회도 해봤고
화도 냈었지
the frustration,
the anger.
I remember what that felt like.
그게 무슨
기분인지 알아
그런 일이 있을 때
내 편에 서준 건
And I also remember that
the only person who stood by me
through all of it was you.
바로 너였어
넌 혼자가 아니야
You're not alone in this, Kono.
얘기 하고
싶을 때
When you want to talk,
I'll be here.
내가 옆에 있을게
♪ ♪
You never gave that video
to the DOD, did you, Joe?
국방부에 비디오
안 보내셨죠?
그래
No.
있잖아요?
You know what?
두 분이선 친구지만
저한텐 아버지에요
I know he was your friend,
but he was my father.
Whatever it is you're trying
to protect me from,
저를 보호 하려는건
알지만 전 괜찮습니다
I can handle it,
you understand me?
Did you ever think that maybe
너만 보호 하려는게
아니라곤 생각 안 해봤어?
you're not the only one
I'm trying to protect?
What are you
talking about?
무슨 말 이에요?
Risk versus reward, Steve.
보상에는
위험도 따른다
How much damage are you willing
to do to your family,
네 가족 명예에
흠을 내고 싶은거냐?
to your family's name?
'Cause whatever's on that video
그 비디오
안 에 있는게
is not going
to bring your father back.
네 아버지를
돌려주진 않을거다
I need to know.
알아야 해요
나엘남캐 한글자막/싱크
수정금지/자유배포